<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EA Helsinki</title>
    <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on EA Helsinki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.altruismi.fi/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/contact/</guid>
      <description>This is the contact page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Altruism</title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/effective-altruism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/effective-altruism/</guid>
      <description>Effective altruism is a philosophy and social movement that applies evidence and reason to determine the most effective ways to improve the world. Effective altruists aim to consider all causes and actions, and then act in the way that brings about the greatest positive impact. It is this broad evidence-based approach that distinguishes effective altruism from traditional altruism or charity. While a substantial proportion of effective altruists have focused on the nonprofit sector, the philosophy of effective altruism applies much more broadly, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/key-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/key-terms/</guid>
      <description>Key EA Terms 
Core Ideas Effective altruism: Effective altruism (EA) is the name of a growing social movement and an idea – based around using evidence and reason to find the most effective possible ways of doing good in the world. An effective altruist is someone who identifies with and tries to act according to the principles of Effective Altruism.
Cost-effectiveness: The cost-effectiveness of a charitable intervention simply refers to how much good it does with a certain amount of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/organizations/</guid>
      <description>Organizations 
AMF: The Against Malaria Foundation (AMF) is a non-profit that funds the distribution of long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLIN) to areas with high incidence of malaria, mostly in Africa. GiveWell has recommended AMF as a top charity several times. As of 2019, GiveWell estimated that it costs AMF about $4.22 to distribute one LLIN and $3,000 per equivalent under-5 year old life saved.
Animal Charity Evaluators investigates the most effective ways of reducing non-human animal suffering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Material</title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/reading-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/reading-material/</guid>
      <description>Reading Material 
A lot of material has been developed on how we can go about doing a lot of good. Here is some of the best.
If you like TED talks, watch Peter Singer’s The Why and How of Effective Altruism or check out any of the other TED talks and presentations on effective altruism. The Life You Can Save (Singer’s first book on Effective Altruism) in 3 minutes is also a great watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/_footer-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/_footer-left/</guid>
      <description> More on EA  Intro to effective altruism Video: The Why and How of Effective Altruism Giving 101: The Basics Doing Good Better by Will MacAskill Centre for Effective Altruism  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/_footer-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/_footer-right/</guid>
      <description> Useful links  effectivealtruism.org 80,000 Hours GiveWell The Life You Can Save Centre for Effective Altruism Rethink Charity  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_first_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_first_section_text/</guid>
      <description>Effective altruism is about using evidence and reason to make the world a better place as much as we can, with whatever resources we want to commit to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_second_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_second_section_text/</guid>
      <description>Effective Altruism Helsinki is a welcoming community dedicated to promoting, inspiring and supporting one another to achieve altruistic goals. We organize meetups on every first Thursday of the month, as well as occasional workshops and discussion groups. These are announced on Facebook and our mailing list. You can join our mailing list by emailing subscribe ea-helsinki your.email@address to majordomo@helsinki.fi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_third_section_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.altruismi.fi/en/homepage/_third_section_text/</guid>
      <description>Since most of our members are students or recent graduates, we are especially focused on helping each other find the career choices that will do the most good. Research suggests that thinking carefully about what you do can allow you to have at least dozens of times more impact. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to meet one of our organizers to discuss how you could find the best ways for you to do the most good, you can fill in our 1-1 application form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>